A Guide to the Records of the Communications Office of Governor Ralph Northam, 2018-2022.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Communications Office of Governor Ralph Northam,
2018-2022.
The Library of Virginia
53535
Virginia. Office of the Governor. Communications Office.
1.05 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
Administrative Information
Arranged by series.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions
Acquisition Information
Accession 53529 was transferred by the Office of the Governor, Jan 7, 2022.
Historical Information
The Communications Office is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state government. During the administration of Governor Ralph Northam the Office was responsible for developing communication strategy, communicating with the public, handling relations with the press, providing advice/guidance on agency public communications, and prepping the Governor and staff for media engagements, press conferences, interviews and editorial board meetings, as well as coordinating messaging and leading the statewide communications response during the COVID-19 pandemic. The Office assisted with the creation of press releases, executive orders, proclamations and speeches.
Scope and Content
The Records of the Communications Office of Governor Ralph Northam, 2018-2021, consist of 3 archival boxes and are divided into 3 series. Series have been designated for (I) Elena Yarmosky, 2019-2021; (II) Chelyen Davis, 2018-2022; and (III) Grant Neely, 2019-2021. These records document the meetings, activities, discussions, policy decisions, and recommendations the Communications Office and include topical files, speeches and notes. The majority of each series consists of notes on meetings, issues, and projects, as well as notes on the creation of briefings, statewide messaging and speeches.
Contents List
- Records of the Communcations Office of Governor Ralph Northam, 2018-2021.
  - Series I: Records of Alena Yarmosky, 2019-2021., Extent: .35 cu. ft.
    Alena Yarmosky served as Press Secretary, 2018 Dec-2022 Jan, and had a dual role as Senior Communication Advisor, 2020 Dec-2022 Jan.
    - Budget (2022-2024), 2021. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Covid 19, 2020-2021. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Messaging, 2019-2021. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 2019-2021. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Series II: Records of Chelyen Davis, 2018-2022., Extent: .35 cu. ft.
    Chelyen Davis served as Deputy Communications Director, 2018 Jan-2022 Jan. Also served as Acting Communications Director, 2019-June-Oct.
    - Gov. Northam biographical information, 2018. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Medicaid Coverage Op-Ed (draft), undated. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Speeches, 2018. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Speeches, undated. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Speeches - State of the Commonwealth, 2022. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Washington Post Editorial Board, 2019. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Series III: Records of Grant Neely, 2018-2021., Extent: .35 cu. ft.
    Grant Neely served as Chief Communications Officer, 2019 Oct-2022 Jan.
    - Covid 19, 2020. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 2018-2021. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Notes, 2020 Feb-Apr. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Notes, 2020 May-Aug. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Notes, 2020 Sept-2021 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Notes, undated. (Box 3, Folder 11)